

RÉSUMÉ

## **Kia ora. Hello.** I'm Dan Newman, an experienced Design Leader and Designer from Te Whanganui-a-Tara/Wellington, Aotearoa/New Zealand.

I've led, hired, and managed growing design teams in several startups and digital agencies, across timezones, in offices, and remotely, all while continuing to work directly on projects. I'd love to keep doing that with fun, genuine, creative people working for an organisation with a real purpose and vision.

Email dan@newman.is Mobile +64 21 0266 3446

Website <u>dan.newman.is</u>

Location Wellington
Timezone GMT+12 / NZST
Citizenship New Zealand
Ethnicity Pākehā

Born 1982

SKILLS

I take great pride in supporting creative teams to do their best work with an empathetic and encouraging leadership style. In over two decades working hands-on and directing teams, I've designed everything from websites, apps, installations, and design systems to conferences, keynotes, swag, office fitouts, posters, billboards, advertising campaigns, logos, and brands. I'm experienced in the following areas of design and team management:

- $\boldsymbol{-}$  Visual design, art direction, and typography
- Branding, identity design, and design systems
- Advertising, marketing, and growth experimentation
- User research, usability testing, and prototyping
- Managing multidisciplinary teams and projects
- Leading design ideation and the creative process
- Front-end engineering support and collaborationShipping and refining quality user experiences

A selection of projects I have worked on is available at dan.newman.is/#archiving

EXPERIENCE

Axiom

Head of Design 2022—Present Remote

**Knolling**Director / Advisor

2021—Present Remote

Stedi Design Lead 2021—2022

Remote

Springload Creative Director 2017—2021

Wellington, New Zealand

Koordinates Head of Design 2015—2017

Wellington, New Zealand

Xero Creative Director

2012—2015 Wellington, New Zealand

Creative Director 2010—2012 London, United Kingdom

Flightless

**Tigerspike** 

Designer / Front-end Developer 2007—2009 Wellington, New Zealand

The D.A. (Freelance)
Designer / Founder
2001—2007
Whanganui, New Zealand

Axiom is an observability application for developers.

I'm helping grow the design team, establishing our design direction, brand, GTM strategy and metrics, product onboarding, UX, marketing website, emails, blogs, conferences, ads and swag.

Knolling is a design consultancy and family office.

I run the business with my partner. We work independently with various clients (primarily B2B tech startups) on their design and marketing strategies. I also mentor designers and design leaders.

Stedi is a SaaS startup building EDI software.

I worked with a team of designers and frontend engineers to establish the design direction, brand, and marketing efforts for the launch of their first developer-focused products.

Springload is a digital design and development agency.

I led and hired a large creative team (through a merger), as well as pitching, delivering, and improving the quality of projects. I also directed and designed the award-winning Klim Type Foundry site.

Koordinates is a suite of geospatial data management tools.

I joined as their first designer and hired a team to help with a major redesign of the product. We also designed brand and sales collateral, as well as the marketing and help websites.

Xero is online accounting software.

I led and hired an internal design team through intense growth, while directing and designing xero.com, Xerocon, OOH and digital campaigns, and creative for marketing, sales, and product teams.

Tigerspike (now Concentrix Catalyst) is a mobile agency.

I joined the London office as it was established, and helped design some of the first iPhone and iPad applications for The Economist, Al Jazeera, Virgin, The Telegraph, and France Télévisions.

Flightless is a design studio.

I worked with the team to design and build websites, interactive exhibitions, and brands for clients like Icebreaker, Nintendo, SPCA Pik Pok, Te Papa (Museum of New Zealand), and Spy Valley Wines.

The D.A. was a design studio for freelancers.

I co-founded a company to help students get freelance design work and business experience before graduating. I also freelanced for various clients designing logos, print collateral, and websites. **TESTIMONIALS** 

I'm extremely grateful to Dan for always pushing us to deliver truly beautiful work, while building and mentoring a powerhouse team (from 2 people to nearly 20), under incredibly challenging pressures and timeframes. Thanks to Dan's talent, commitment and resilience our work and our team delivered to an extremely high standard on every project.

We couldn't have scaled the team or maintained our high quality standards without him. It's an understatement to say Dan had a huge and very positive impact on Xero.

— Philip Fierlinger (Head of Design, Xero)

[Dan] you are an absolute superhuman. I'll always remember when I first met you for a coffee after you were hired as my boss. You asked "How can I help?".

I appreciate so much how you listened and included everyone in developing our team and practices. The care and sensitivity in how you mentor people and their work, realising that words really matter, and people receive things differently.

I have seen the people and work flourish, and how thoughtfully you've looked after team members facing challenges. You have been the bedrock of our wonderful, fun, and inclusive team culture, thank you for all you have given (and all the sleep you have lost!).

- Lizy Cretney (Design Director, Springload)

Dan is one of the most organised and dedicated designers I have met. He has a natural energy, warmth, and drive, which I believe reflects in his approach to life and his design work.

- Rick Hargreaves (Thesis Advisor, Whanganui School of Design)

AWARDS

AGDA Awards: Pinnacle, Distinction, and Judge's Choice (x6)
Red Dot Award: Best of the Best (x2)
Type Directors Club: Certificate of Typographic Excellence
Communication Arts Award of Excellence: Typography Annual
Designers Institute of New Zealand Best Awards: Gold (x2)
Designers Institute of New Zealand Best Awards: Silver (x6)
Designers Institute of New Zealand Best Awards: Bronze (x5)
Designers Institute of New Zealand Best Awards: Finalist (x14)

A full list of awards is available at dan.newman.is/#employable

EDUCATION

Scholarship: Masters, Interaction Design (Leonardo Project)
Nottingham University & FH Oberösterreich
2005—2006

Nottingham, United Kingdom / Hagenberg, Austria

Masters, Computer Graphic Design (Honours)
Whanganui School of Design & Waikato University
2001—2006
Whanganui, New Zealand